Kyle Bini

A full stack software engineer with a design background. My previous career as a landscape designer has been invaluable in my engineering education to allow me to visualize and develop creative solutions to problems, while grounding me in the development process.

EXPERIENCE

General Assembly, Boston, MA (Remote) — Software Engineering Immersive

MAY 2020 - AUGUST 2020

Developed four projects during a 12-week (500+ hrs) immersive program in software engineering. Engaged in fast-paced, meaningful lessons to explore full stack applications, programs and frameworks. Projects focused on developing single-page applications in a RESTful style.

FEATURED PROJECTS

Back in 10! – A calendar application designed to promote wellness activities during daily life (*React.js*, *Express.js*, *Axios*, *Bootstrap*) **PlusOne** – (Team Project) A social event application allowing users to post an event they are attending and allow other users to RSVP (*React.js*, *Express.js*, *Axios*, *SASS*)

Take A Hike! - A tracking application allowing users to create and log hikes (*JavaScript*, *Express.js*, *Ajax*, *SASS*)

D.A. Dunlevy, Poolesville, MD — Landscape Designer

NOVEMBER 2015 - FEBRUARY 2020

Developed and managed projects from initial site analysis through conceptual development, schematic plans and detailed construction documentation.

Maintained multiple projects simultaneously at varying stages of completion.

Built and fostered client relationships as the main point person on upwards of 12 projects at a time.

Managed install crews, oversaw project layout and installation throughout the construction process.

Caesars Entertainment Corp., Atlantic City, NJ — CRM Coordinator

JANUARY 2015 - NOVEMBER 2015

Built customer offers for targeted audiences and manipulated mail files for all direct mail and email campaigns.

Executed project tasks independently and as part of a team to meet tight deadlines and send offers on time, within scope and on budget. Performed QA on all materials for errors and accuracy.

Managed several projects simultaneously and coordinated with departments around the country to track and organize each project stage.

New Jersey, 08520

(609) 558-5331

Email: kbini28@gmail.com

LinkedIn: <u>in/kylebini</u>
Github: kbini28

Portfolio: kbini28.github.io

LANGUAGES, FRAMEWORKS & SKILLS

React.is Express.js JavaScript HTML Heroku **Ajax** Axios iQuery **Bootstrap** MongoDB CSS/SASS Mongoose Django Node.js Github PostgreSQL Handlebars Python

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

Illustrator Photoshop
InDesign Vectorworks

EDUCATION

Delaware Valley University Doylestown, PA B.S. Environmental Design

Graduated 2013

ORGANIZATIONS

Sigma Nu Fraternity
Primary Charitable
Organization –
Susan G. Komen Breast
Cancer Foundation